You just saw that NumPy functions like mean operate on the array as a whole but
لقد رأيت للتو دوال NumPy مثل دالة المتوسط تعمل على الصفيف بالكامل
in many cases it might make sense to calculate the operation by row or
ولكن في حالات كثيرة قد يكون من المنطقي إجراء حساب للعملية حسب الصف
by column.
.أو العمود
For example, consider the array of subway riders that you just looked at,
على سبيل المثال، فكّر في ،ركاب قطار الأنفاق الذي اطلعت على تجربته للتو
where each column is a station and each row is a date.
حيث يمثل كل عمود محطة .وكل صف تاريخًا
It might make sense to take the mean ridership per day across all subway
قد يكون من المنطقي استخراج متوسط عدد الركاب كل يوم عبر جميع محطات
stations like you just did but you might also want to take the mean ridership for
قطار الأنفاق مثلما فعلت للتو ولكنك قد ترغب أيضًا في استخراج متوسط عدد الركاب
each station or for each date.
.لكل محطة أو كل تاريخ
Most functions built into NumPy take an axis argument for this reason,
وتستخدم معظم الدوال المدمجة في NumPy ،وسيطة محور لهذا السبب
which can be either zero or one.
.قد تكون صفرًا أو واحدًا
If the axis is zero, then the function will be calculated for
،إذا كان المحور يساوي الصفر فسيتم حساب الدالة
each column and if the axis is one, it will be calculated for each row.
،لكل عمود وإذا كان المحور يساوي واحدًا .فسيتم حساب الدالة لكل صف
I find it hard to remember which axis is zero and which is one so,
وأجد أنه من الصعب تذكُّر المحور الذي يساوي الصفر والمحور الذي يساوي واحد ولهذا السبب
I always just try it out and see before using the axis argument.
أحاول دائمًا تجربة هذا وأرى النتيجة .قبل استخدام وسيطة المحور
To get some practice, I want you to write some code to find the mean
وللتمرين على هذا، أريدك أن تكتب تعليمة برمجية لمعرفة متوسط عدد الركاب&lrm; لكل يوم بالنسبة
ridership per day for each subway station.
لكل محطة .قطار أنفاق
Then, out of all the subway stations, return the maximum and
وبعد هذا، من بين جميع محطات قطار الأنفاق قم بإرجاع الحدين الأقصى والأدنى لعدد الركاب
the minimum ridership per day.
.لكل يوم